Thomas Wood Stevens papers, 1895-1984 (bulk 1897-1937)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series VI: Published Works and Manuscripts, 1896-1984
  - Plays, Scenarios, Monologues, 1905-1941
    - Monologues. 1928-1929 (Box 58, Folder 2)
      "Mary of Magdala"
      Dierdre"
    - Venus and Adolphus. 1938 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Kings and Queens of England. 1940 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Knights of Terror, a play for boys. 1940 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Two Radio Scripts prepared by Thomas Wood Stevens from: Barbara, by Kenneth Sawyer Goodman and Silver Grayhound, by Thomas Wood Stevens. 1941 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Scenarios, plans, programs, pageants, and skits (fragments). (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Lincoln, or The Armstrong Trial Episode (a fragment) (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Friend Mary (a Lincoln episode). No Date (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Highways Cross. ca. 1920 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Don Juan. 1922 (Box 58a, Folder 1)
    - Don Juan, (prompt copies). (Box 58a, Folder 2)
    - Circle of Chalk. 1932 (Box 58a, Folder 3)
    - Circle of Chalk, (prompt copy). (Box 58a, Folder 4)
    - The Chalk Circle. I. S. Richter version. (Box 58a, Folder 5)
    - The Chalk Circle, Ethel Van der Veer version, (prompt copy). (Box 58a, Folder 6)
    - I Confess, with William Beyer. 1930 (Box 58a, Folder 7)
    - I Confess, (revisions, notes, etc.). (Box 58a, Folder 8)
    - I Confess, (correspondence). (Box 58a, Folder 9)
    - The Triumph of Punchinello, a Pantomime Sequence. 1916 (Box 58b, Folder 1)
    - Poe, with B. Iden Payne, (Acts III and IV only). 1919-1920 (Box 58b, Folder 2)
    - Tour du Monde. 1929 (Box 58b, Folder 3)
    - Tour du Monde, (prompt copies). (Box 58b, Folder 4-5)
    - Tour du Monde, (miscellaneous material). (Box 58b, Folder 6)
    - The Real American Romance, vol. 2, "The Golden Quest." 1909 (Box 58b)
      Published by W. H. Wise and Company as part of a series of 13 volumes, edited by Edwin Markham.
    - Camille in Roaring Camp, (2 copies). 1928 (Box 58c)
    - Camille in Roaring Camp, (prompt copies). (Box 58c, Folder 1-3)
    - Camille in Roaring Camp, (correspondence). 1928-1940 (Box 58c, Folder 4-5)
    - Camille in Roaring Camp, Santa Fe Fiesta Production. 1932 (Box 58c, Folder 6)
    - Camille in Roaring Camp, Thomas Wood Stevens' notes. (Box 58c, Folder 7)
    - Caesar's God, a Byzantine Masque, with Kenneth Sawyer Goodman, Chicago: The Stage Guild. 1913 (Box 59)
    - The Chaplet of Pan, a masque, with Wallace Rice, Chicago: The Stage Guild. 1912 (Box 59)
    - The Daimio's Head, a masque of old Japan, with Kenneth Sawyer Goodman, Chicago: The Art Institute. 1911 (Box 59)
    - The Daimio's Head, a masque of old Japan, with Kenneth Sawyer Goodman, Chicago: The Stage Guild. 1915 (Box 59)
    - The Daimio's Head & Other Masques, with Kenneth Sawyer Goodman, Chicago: The Stage Guild. 1912 (Box 59)
      Includes also, Montezuma and Quetzal's Bowl.
    - Holbein in Blackfriars, with Kenneth Sawyer Goodman, Chicago: The Stage Guild. 1913 (Box 59)
    - Masque of Quetzal's Bowl, with Kenneth Sawyer Goodman. (Box 59)
      Written for the 2nd anniversary of the house warming of the Cliff-Dwellers.
    - Masques of East and West, with Kenneth Sawyer Goodman, New York: Vaughan & Gomme. 1914 (Box 59)
      Edited by Wallace Rice with a foreword by Percy MacKaye.
    - The Nursery Maid of Heaven, and Other Plays, New York: Appleton and Company. 1926 (Box 59)
    - Rainald and the Red Wolf, with Kenneth Sawyer Goodman, Chicago. 1914 (Box 59)
      The masque of the Pilgrims and the townsfolk of Lavayne. Written for the Mardi Gras Festival of the Art Student's League.
    - Ryland, with Kenneth Sawyer Goodman. Chicago: The Stage Guild. 1912 (Box 59)
    - Three Wishes, New York: Frank Shay. 1920 (Box 59)
      A comedy in one act. The Stage Guild Plays, no. 4.
    - Mayorga, Margaret, Representative One-act Plays by American Authors, Boston: Little, Brown and Company. 1923 (Box 59)
      Contains Ryland, pp. 371-396, a comedy by Thomas Wood Stevens and Kenneth Sawyer Goodman.
    - Sanford, Anne P., Pageants of our Nation, Eastern States: New York, Pennsylvania, New Jersey, Maryland, New York: Dodd, Mead. 1929 (Box 59)
      Contains the first movement from The Pageant of Newark, Pp. 269-296, by Thomas Wood Stevens.
    - Shay, Frank, ed., The Appleton Book of Christmas Plays, New York: D. Appleton and Company. 1929 (Box 59)
      Contains The Duquesne Christmas Mystery, pp. 179-188, a nativity play by Thomas Wood Stevens.
    - The Nursery Maid of Heaven, Baker's Plays, Boston, Massachusetts and Denver, Colorado. 1926 (Box 59)
  - Miscellaneous Published Works, 1901-1940
    Unless otherwise indicated, publications are authored by Thomas Wood Stevens.
    - The Theatre from Athens to Broadway, New York: D. Appleton and Company. 1932 (Box 60)
      With drawings by the author. Inscribed, "to the Thomas Wood Stevens Memorial Collection on the occasion of the author's 100th birthday, January 26, 1980, by his daughter Phoebe Stevens Mera."
    - "The Autumn of Love, a Poem," Harpers Magazine, p. 147. 1905 (Box 60)
    - "Three Birds," The Outer's Book: A Magazine of Outdoor interest, p. 1093. September 1907 (Box 60)
      Sonnets.
    - "The Pageant," Poetry: a Magazine of Verse, p. 82. May 1918 (Box 60)
    - "The Cactus," Poetry: a Magazine of Verse, p. 173 July 1940 (Box 60)
    - "Desert Processional," Theatre Arts Monthly, p. 306-313. April 1938 (Box 60)
    - Markham, Edwin, ed., The Real America in Romance, New York: H. W. Wise and Company. 1909-1927 (Box 60)
      Volume 2 of 15 volumes, "The Gold Quest: The Age of Conquest, 1506-1547," by Thomas Wood Stevens. Note by Mrs. Stevens on the title page.
    - The Etching of Cities, Chicago Society of Etchers. 1913 (Box 60)
      325 copies printed.
    - Hold Redmere, with Alden Charles Noble, Ridgewood, New Jersey: Alwil Shop. 1901 (Box 60)
      Number 154 of 450 copies printed on hand-made paper, 50 additional copies printed on Japan vellum.
    - Lettering, New York, Chicago: The Prang Company. 1916 (Box 60)
      (2 copies).
    - The Unsought Shrine, and Titian, The Boy, Ridgewood, New Jersey, Alwil Shop. 1901 (Box 60)
      Alwil Brochures, Series I., no. 1. This copy lacks cover and frontispiece.
    - Westward Under Vega, New York: Covicci-Friede. 1938 (Box 60)
    - Atchison, Topeka and Sante Fe Railway System: The California Limited. 1902-1903 (Box 60)
      Illustrated by H. E. Townsend. "This is one of the books Mr. Stevens designed and arranged (probably wrote) when in the employ of the Sante Fe Railroad as assistant to the Advertising Department. The illustrator, Townsend, was his closest friend for forty years. Had been associated with the Blue Sky Press until it closed." Note of Mrs. Stevens.
    - Atchison, Topeka and Sante Fe Railway System: The California Limited Log Book. Sante Fe Route. 1901? (Box 60)
    - "A Song for Arizona," extract from Out West. August 1902 (Box 60)
    - "Westward Under Vega," extracts from Survey Graphic. December 1937, February 1938 (Box 60)
    - The Theatre from Athens to Broadway. (Box 61)
      Original draft: chapters 1-16, 20-22, Typescript: chapters 1-6, 8-16.
    - The Theatre from Athens to Broadway. (Box 62)
      40 original drawings by Thomas Wood Stevens.
  - Prompt Books
    - Anon: Jacob and Esau. William Poel's arrangement. (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Fletcher, John: The Elder Brother. (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Goldoni, Carlo: The Servant of Two Masters. (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Isben, H.: The Warriors at Helgeland. (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Kaiser, George: Gas. (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Leivick, H.: The Golem. (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Rives, Amelie: Love-in-a-Mist. (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Sheridan: The Rivals. 1924-1925 (Box 63, Folder 8)
      Edited by Harrison Grey Fiske for the 150th anniversary tour.
    - Sudermann, H.: Johannes. (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - All's Well That Ends Well, (5 copies). (Box 64)
    - As You Like It. (Box 64)
    - Comedy of Errors, (2 copies). (Box 64)
    - Coriolanus. (Box 64)
    - Hamlet. (Box 64)
    - King Henry VIII, (2 copies). (Box 64)
    - Merry Wives of Windsor. (Box 64)
    - A Midsummer Nights Dream. (Box 64)
    - Romeo and Juliet, (2 copies). (Box 64)
    - The Taming of the Shrew. (Box 64)
    - The Tempest. (Box 64)
    - Two Gentlemen of Verona, (3 copies). (Box 64)
    - Winter's Tale, (2 copies). (Box 64)
    - Cannan, Gilbert: Everybody's Husband. (Box 65)
    - Dryden: All for Love. (Box 65)
      In Everyman edition of Restoration Plays from Dryden to Farquhar.
    - Dumas, A.: The Tower of Nesle. (Box 65)
      Translated by Adam L. Gowans (2 copies).
    - Euripides: The Trojan Women. (Box 65)
      Translated by Gilbert Murray
    - Euripides: Hippolytus. (Box 65)
      Translated by Gilbert Murray. "Prompt Book for Hypothetical Production" in Advanced Dramatic Production, University of Michigan, by Muriel Foster.
    - Euripides: Iphigenia in Tauris. (Box 65)
      Translated by Gilbert Murray.
    - Lady Gregory: The Golden Apple. (Box 65)
    - Galsworthy: Escape. (Box 65)
    - Galsworthy: The Skin Game. (Box 65)
    - Garnett, Edward: The Feud. (Box 65)
    - Gayley, Charles Mills: The Star of Bethlehem. (Box 65)
    - Glaspell, Susan: Alison's House. (Box 65)
    - Goldoni: The Fan. (Box 65)
      Henry B. Fuller, Translator.
    - Ibsen, H.: The League of Youth. (Box 65)
      In Modern Library Edition.
    - Moliere: Les Femmes Savantes. (Box 66)
      Translated by Curtis Hidden Page
    - Moody, W. V.: The Faith Healer. (Box 66)
    - Parker, Maude May: Louisiana. A Pageant of Yesterday and Today. (Box 66)
    - Phillips, Stephen: Paolo and Francesca. (Box 66)
    - Poel, William: Love's Constancy. (Box 66)
      An episode in the play of Edward the Third, arranged in on act by William Poel.
    - Selby, C.: Robert Macaire. or The Two Murderers. (2 copies). (Box 66)
    - Shaw, George Bernard: You Never Can Tell. (Box 66)
      In Plays: Pleasant and Unpleasant, vol. 2.
    - Sheridan, R. B.: The Rivals. (Box 66)
    - Sudraka: The Little Clay Cart. (Box 66)
      A Hindu drama attributed to King Shudraka. Music cues only.
    - Swinburne, A. C.: Atlanta in Calydon. (Box 66)
      In Swinburne's Dramas, edited by Arthur Beatty.
    - Synge, J. M.: The Shadow of the Glen. (Box 66)
    - Wilde, Oscar: A Florentine Tragedy. (Box 66)
    - Wilde, Oscar: The Importance of Being Earnest. (Box 66)
      In Plays.
- Series VII: Etchings
  - Etchings: catalogs, exhibits, pamphlets. (Box 67)
  - 26 original etchings by Thomas Wood Stevens. (Box 68)
  - 17 original etchings by Thomas Wood Stevens. (Box 69)
  - 15 original etchings by Thomas Wood Stevens. (Box 70)